Guide to the Records of the Office of the Treasurer (Muriel L. Mantel) RG.10
New York University Archives
Records of the Office of the Treasurer (Muriel L. Mantel)
1886-1993
1910-1979
New York University Archives
New York University. Office of the Treasurer
Mantel, Muriel
RG.10
30 Linear Feet (74 boxes)
This collection contains administrative records of Muriel L. Mantel, Administrative Assistant to NYU's Vice President of Business Affairs and Treasurer and later NYU's Associate Treasurer. The collection is mainly related to financial records and property records.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject and then chronologically within each subject in processed series.
The files are grouped into five series:
Series
General Administration
Washington Square
University Heights
Medical Center
Unprocessed Materials
Related Material at the New York University Archives
Administrative Papers of Office of the Treasurer 1910-1963: The Papers of LeRoy Elwood Kimball.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains administrative files, mostly financial records, from the years that Muriel L. Mantel worked in the Office of the Treasurer and earlier. The records were received directly from Muriel Mantel in 1993.
The majority of the records are financial and include: papers having to do with real estate transactions and insurance, property taxes, building plans and blueprints, wills, trusts and endowments, planning committees, bills, budget information, press publications, patents, and correspondence. Particularly useful or relevant for researchers is material relating to NYU's property acquisitions and development, especially having to do with the building of the Medical Center, including information about buying buildings, mergers, mortgage papers, building blueprints, maintenance reports, building contracts and reports, lease agreements, tenant eviction notices, demolitions and renovations, building inspections, and community negotiations.
Biography of Muriel Mantel
Muriel L. Mantel held several positions in the Office of the Treasurer for many years. She began working as a secretary in the Office of the Treasurer while still an undergraduate. She was promoted to the position of Administrative Assistant to NYU's Vice President of Business Affairs and Treasurer in 1962. She received a B.S. from NYU's School of Commerce, Accounts and Finance in 1949 and her M.B.A. from the same in 1966. She lived in New York City, mainly in Queens. She retired in 1993.
Sources:
Mantel, Muriel L, Biographical File, New York University Archives
Access Restrictions
Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection.
Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted.
Provenance
This collection was received in three accessions from Muriel Mantel in 1993.
Maps.; Photographs.; Correspondence.; blueprints (reprographic copies); Universities and colleges |z United States |x Administration.; Administrative records.; Universities and colleges |z United States |x Finance.; Universities and colleges |z United States |x Real Estate.; Clippings (information artifacts); New York (N.Y.).; Baughman, George F., 1915-2004; New York University. Medical Center; NYU Press; New York University. College of Dentistry; Chase, Harry Woodburn, 1883-1955; Ladd, Kate Macy, 1863-1945; Nichols, William H., 1852-1930; Smith, Rufus D. (Rufus Daniel), 1884-1953; New York University. Office of the Treasurer; New York University. Council; New York University. University Heights; New York University. Washington Square Campus; New York University -- Buildings; New York University -- Real property
- Series I: General Administration
  - Accounts, List of, ca.1933-1937, 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adams, E. Sherman, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Administration Charts - Organization/Properties, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Aetna Life Insurance Company Mortgage, 1936-1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Agreements and Contracts, Miscellaneous, 1956-1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Amended Charter for New York University, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Bank Note Company Mortgage, 1936-1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American College Public Relations Association. Annual Survey of Ed. Philanthropy, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Council on Education, 1950-1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Annual Financial Reports of Schools, 1959-1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Annual Report of the Vice President and Treasurer, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Annual Report of the Vice President and Treasurer, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Annual Report of the Vice President and Treasurer, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Analysis of Clerical Salaries, 1938-1944 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Armsey, James W., 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Art Collection of New York University, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Art Projects for the Army and Navy, 1941-1941 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Authorization for Facsimile Signature on Checks, 1930-1951 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Baughman, George F. - University of Florida, 1952-1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Baughman, George F. - Southern Association of College and University Business Officers, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Baughman, George F. -Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Billing, Cumulative for Gas and Electricity, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Blankfort, Walter A., 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Board of Trustees, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Board of Trustees, 1966-1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bonds and Mortgages - New York University, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bond Premiums, Amoritization of, 1939-1945 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bookstore, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Booz, Allen and Hamilton - Listening Post Data, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Booz, Allen and Hamilton - Organization Survey, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Booz, Allen and Hamilton - Survey, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Breuer, Marcel, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Letter from Breuer to George F. Baughman, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Letter from Breuer to George F. Baughman, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Letter from Hamilton Smith to George F. Baughman, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Transmittal of Photos from Breuer to George F. Baughman, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Memo from George F. Baughman to Dean Thorndike Saville, NYU, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Letter from Margaret Firmage to George F. Baughman, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Memo from Dean Thorndike Saville to Mr. Baughman, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Memo from George F. Baughman to Chancellor Heald, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Letter from George F. Baughman to Mr. Breuer, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Letter from Margaret Firmage to George F. Baughman, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Brown, Wheelock, Harris, Stevens, Inc. Mortgages, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Budget, 1933-1935 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Budget - Hendershot/Baughman, 1955-1958 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Budget Statement, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Budget Statement, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Building Maintenance Report; Building Improvement Report, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Building Service Employee Contracts, 1938-1952 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Building Service Employee International Union, 1938-1951 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bursar, 1917-1925 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Business Offices - NYU, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Business Office Committees, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Capital Campaign, 1964-1973 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Capital Campaign, 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1909-1917 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1918-1921 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1921-1926 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1926-1936 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Central Administration of Student Affairs, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Charts of Operations, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Check Signer (Todd Photograph Co.), 1920-1955 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - City Sales Tax, 1933, 1947-1951 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Cleaning Committee, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - College and University Business Magazine, 1953-1956 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Comparative Budget Statements and Statements of Alternation & Reconstruction Costs & Continuing Commitments, 1937-1948 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Comptroller, 1925-1930 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Comptroller, 1930-1936 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Comptroller, 1936-1944 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Comptroller, 1937-1944 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Comptroller - Tax and Legislation Meetings, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Comptroller - World's Fair, 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Connecticut General Life Insurance Mortgage, 1936-1952 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Controller, 1953-1956 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Consolidated Mortgages Correspondence, 1936-1953 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Consolidated Mortgages, Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1936-1938 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Consolidated Mortgages, Hampton Institute, N.Y. Hospital, U.S. Trust Co., Williams College, 1936-1938 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Consolidated Mortgages, Henry Street Settlement, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Consolidated Mortgages, Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1939-1941 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Consolidated Mortgages, Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1942-1947 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Consolidated Mortgages, Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1946-1950 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Consolidated Mortgages, Letters to Bond Holders re: Treasurer's Rpts., 1938-1951 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Consolidated Mortgages, Statements, Schedules and Maps, 1942-1951 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Cooperative Committee of NYU for Emergency Relief, 1930-1932 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Council Dinner - Hotel Manhattan, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Council Dinner - East Room, Waldorf-Astoria, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Council Dinner - Biltmore, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Council Dinner - East Room, Waldorf-Astoria, 1918 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Council Dinner - East Room, Waldorf-Astoria, 1919 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Council Dinner - East Room, Waldorf-Astoria, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Council Dinner - Waldorf Apartment, Waldorf-Astoria, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Council Dinner - Waldorf-Astoria, 1922 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Council Dinner - Century Club, 1922 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Council Dinner - Waldorf Apartment, Waldorf-Astoria, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Council Dinner - State Apartment, Waldorf-Astoria, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Council Dinner - Waldorf Apartment, Waldorf-Astoria, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Council Dinner - Waldorf-Astoria, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Council Dinner - Waldorf Apartment, Waldorf-Astoria, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Council Dinner - Waldorf-Astoria, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Council Dinner - Waldorf Apartment, Waldorf-Astoria, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Council Dinner - Waldorf Apartment, Waldorf-Astoria, 1927 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Council Dinner - Waldorf Apartment, Waldorf-Astoria, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Council Dinner - Waldorf-Astoria, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Council Dinner - Waldorf-Astoria, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Council Dinner - The Biltmore, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Council Dinner to Mr. Kingsley - Pierre's, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Council Dinner - The Biltmore, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Council Dinner - The Biltmore, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Council and Deans' Dinner - Jansen Suite, Waldorf-Astoria, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Council Dinner - Jade Room, Waldorf-Astoria, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Dinner in honor of Dr. Chase - Waldorf-Astoria, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Council Dinner - Jade Room, Waldorf-Astoria, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Council Dinner - Sert Room, Waldorf-Astoria, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Council Dinner - Jade Room, Waldorf-Astoria, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Council Dinner - Sert Room, Waldorf-Astoria, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Council Dinner - Jade Room, Waldorf-Astoria, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Council Dinner, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Council Dinner, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Council Dinner - Sert Room, Waldorf-Astoria, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Council Dinner - Sert Room, Waldorf-Astoria, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Council Dinner - Sert Room, Waldorf-Astoria, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Council Dinner, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Council Dinner, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Council Dinner (Special), 1944 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Credit Union (Baughman, George), 1956 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Dean's Meetings, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Denver Research Institute (Baughman, George), 1956 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Department of Health, Education and Welfare, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Drainage Facilities, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - East Streets Corporation, 1946-1948 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Electronic Data Processing, 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Consolidated Endowment Fund, 1952-1965 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Consolidated Endowment Fund, 1960-1961 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Consolidated Endowment - Principal Funds, 1963-1965 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Endowment and Expendable Funds, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Endowment, 1961-1968 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Endowments, Statement of, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Jane E. Andrews Estate, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Ruth A. Bruce-Brown Trust (1 of 2), 1950 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Ruth A. Bruce-Brown Trust (2 of 2), 1950 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Will of A. Ogden Butler, 1886 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Al Jolson Estate, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Samuel H. Kress Foundation Gift, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Kate Macy Ladd Fund, 1950-1951 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Kate Macy Ladd Fund, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Kate Macy Ladd Fund, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - William H. Nichols Estate, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Margaret Olivia Sage Estate, 1920 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Theodore Starr Estate, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Theodore Starr Estate, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Esther Hull Tremain Estate, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Arthur S. Tuttle Estate, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - H. Sylvia A. H. G. Wilks Estate (1 of 3), 1951 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - H. Sylvia A. H. G. Wilks Estate (2 of 3), 1951 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - H. Sylvia A. H. G. Wilks Estate (3 of 3), 1951 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Executive Vice Chancellor - May 28, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Executive Vice Chancellor - Publications Review Committee, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Executive Vice Chancellor - Office of Research Service (Dr. Richards, Dr. Harvey, Mr. Roth), 1952-1954 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Executive Vice Chancellor - Assistant to the Ex. Vice Chancellor and Director of the Office of the Budget, 1953-1955 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Executive Vice Chancellor - Non-Commercial Educational Television Station, 1952-1955 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Executive Vice Chancellor - Report of New York University Self-Study Group financed by Carnegie Corporation, 1953-1955 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Facilities Contract, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Second Mortgages, 1959-1967 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Family Educations Rights and Privacy Act, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Federal Reserve Retirement System Mortgage, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Federal Security Agency Office of Higher Education, 1948-1949 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Finance Committee Special Meetings, 1935-1938 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Matters, 1924-1927 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Finance - Record of Income/Payment, 1909, 1922-1924 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Financial Report - New York University, 1953-1954 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Financial Reports, 1950-1956 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Financial Report - Supporting Schedule, 1953-1955 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Financial Reports, 1956-1958 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Fiscal Matters, 1973-1975 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Five Year Fund Raising Program, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Food Services (Flaster, Herbert), 1956 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Food Services - Blaikie, Miller and Hines, 1955-1958 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Foundation Gifts for the Social Sciences, 1953-1954 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Fund for the Advancement of Education- Baughman, George, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Furniture Purchases, 1955-1956 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - General University Survey, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Gifts and Grants - Nature or Purpose, 1953-1954 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Gifts, 1939-1968 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Gifts - Breakdown of Gifts, 1955-1956 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Ford Foundation Gift, 1963-1964 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Government Contracts, 1955-1956 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Government Contracts, 1943-1944 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Guaranty Trust Company of New York (Mortgage), 1951-1956 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Hart, Milton, 1955-1956 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Heald, Henry, Chancellor, 1955-1956 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Henry Woodburn Chase Portrait, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Holiday Schedules, 1963-1993 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Information Office, 1956-1957 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Improvement Projects - Baughman, 1955-1957 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Institute for the Crippled and Disabled, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Institute for Hygiene, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - International Business Machines as used by New York University, 1955-1956 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Inventories of University Buildings - Insurance Purposes, 1905-1906 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Jensen, Grady, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Kimball, LeRoy, 1955-1956 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Labor Union Contracts, 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Lee, James Melven, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Lexington First Avenue Association, 1956-1958 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Lexington First Avenue Association, 1940-1957 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Listening Post Meetings (Taxes and Legislations), 1945-1951 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Listening Post, 1950-1955 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Listening Post, 1955-1956 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - MacCracken Plot, 1924-1925 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Manhattan Storage & Warehouse Co. (Silver Torch Storage), 1912-1957 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Microfilming in case of an Atomic Bomb, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Middle States Association Survey on New York University, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Middle States Association Survey on New York University - Kimball's Annotated Copy), 1949 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Middle States Association Survey on New York University, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Middle States Association Survey Reply, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Middle States Association Survey Reply, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Middle States Association Survey, 1949-1950 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Digest of Middle States Reports, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Minimum Wage Certificate, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Mortgages Payable, 1905-1920 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Mortgages Payable, 1922-1932 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Navy - Advanced Payment Pool Agreement, 1951-1960 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - New York State Educational Department, 1938-1951 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - New York University Club, 1956-1960 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - New York University Press, 1922-1939 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - New York University Press -Publications Contracts, 1932-1950 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - New York University Press Agreements, 1935-1951 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - New York University Press - Agreement between Hollis W. Hering, Under Will of Dr. Daniel W. Hering and NYU Press, 1939-1940 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - New York University Press - Committee on Management, 1949-1950 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - New York University Press, 1945-1954 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - New York University Press, 1950 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - New York University Press - Misc. Material prior to turning over of Press to Mr. Armsey, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - New York University Press Contracts, 1952-1954 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - New York University Press Contracts, 1955-1957 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - New York University Press, 1955-1956 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - New York University Press, 1956-1957 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - New York University Press, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - New York University Press, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - New York University Press Publications, 1940-1952 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - New York University Press - Tax Effect of University Press Operations, 1953-1954 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - New York University Press - Thomas Wolfe Publications, 1953-1954 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - NYU Victory Ship, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Notary Republic, 1912-1926 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Office Manager Employees, 1905-1916 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Office Manager Employees, 1916-1921 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Office Manager Employees, 1921-1933 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Office Manager, 1924-1926 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Office Manager, 1926-1929 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Office Manager, 1929-1941 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Office Manager - Payroll Statistics, 1925 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Office Manager, 1942 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Operating Statement, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Organization Charts, 1932-1933 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Patents - University Committee on Patent Matters, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Patents - College of Dentistry, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Patents - Research Corporation, 1950-1957 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Patents - University Patents, 1934-1958 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Patents - University Patents, 1948-1956 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Patents - Survey of University Patent Policies, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Pending University Matters, 1924-1927 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Personnel, Director of, 1948-1954 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Personnel, Director of - Labor Negotiations and Agreements, 1937-1955 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - University Placement Services, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Planning Committee, 1932 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Planning Committee, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Planning Committee "A Statement on Public Realms", 1950 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Planning Committee, Athletics, 1949-1950 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Planning Committee, College of Dentistry, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Planning Committee, College of Engineering, 1946-1951 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Planning Committee, Graduate School of Business Administration, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Planning Committee, Medical Center Purchasing Report, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Planning Committee Meeting, October 1948 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Planning Committee Meeting, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Planning Committee Meeting, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Planning Committee Meeting, 1937-1944 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Planning Committee Meetings, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Planning Committee Meeting, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Planning Committee - Public Relations, 1949-1950 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Planning Committee - School of Commerce, 1947 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Planning Committee - School of Education, Life-Time Camps, 1949-1950 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Planning Committee - School of Education, 1947-1948 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Planning Committee - School of Retailing Proposed Building, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Planning Committee - Science Building, Washington Square, 1948-1949 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Planning Committee - Slum Clearance, 1949-1952 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Planning Committee - Students Building Purchasing Plot, 1946 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Planning Committee - Washington Square Library, 1928-1947 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Post Office, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Presidential Search, 1974-1975 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Printing, 1905-1925 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Press Releases and Clippings, 1937-1975 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Prizes, 1922-1927 (Box 23, Folder 6)